when I'm lugging all my makeup across
the country or I'm having to spend an
extra 30 minutes to get ready for
something and my friend Andrew's just
sitting on the couch just twiddling his
thumbs while I'm like having to put on
eyeliner in my waterline which means
you're poking in your eye and yeah I
don't have to do it but it makes my eye
look that much better yeah it's
exhausting Gabby to be fair my
girlfriend doesn't do it your girlfriend
doesn't do no makeup nothing well she's
also gay yeah well so am I
Gabby Dunn is our guest right now Gabby
Dunn is a author uh comedian do you
still do standup no I mean I did
storytelling on our book tour okay so
yeah just but just a funny cool chick uh
Gabby Dunn her book bad with money the
imperfect art of getting your financial
together is available online now
you have a book you wrote a book this is
like a non-fiction that is based on the
podcast B with money that is like about
I don't know the genre Financial Memoir
is a thing now uhhuh uh but it's like a
financial Memoir but also like a a help
helpful book okay what um you have a you
have a podcast called bad with money yes
in which you talk to Comedians and PE
funny cool people about being bad with
money tell me about the podcast for
season one so I didn't know anything
about money I would cry about it all the
time that's why I'm like avoiding the
issue I don't even want to talk to you
about money that's what you're here to
talk about it's how much people don't
want to talk about money yes I think
I've had some people be like I love you
so much I can't listen because it gives
me anxiety yeah so I get it yes but I I
started not knowing anything and I would
cry that was like my big thing that I
would cry about and I just was always in
the hole somehow and like always had
debt and never talked to anyone about it
and and never like it was like my secret
shame and then I had the opportunity to
do a podcast and they were like well do
you want to do something about lgbtq
issues do you want to do something about
like sex positivity and I was like
actually the thing that I cry about
every day is money maybe we should just
expose that so this the first run
towards it I know so the first season
which is super healthy uh so the first
season the thing you're most scared to
talk about why don't I start a show
about it I mean that's nuts well good
for you okay so the first season was me
mostly talking to Comedians and other
artists and just sort of being like how
do you make money like how do you do
this like what's going on what what's
your situation and I I you know moving
to LA from New York I didn't realize
like oh everyone some people have their
parents money or some people have uh
side jobs that I don't know about or
whatever so I would compare myself so
much to other people without knowing
that they their situations were so
different from mine y so I would like I
you know we would have the same income
but I you know I take care of some
family members and I had uh student
loans and and whatever and then I would
compare myself to people who would who
didn't have any student loans or were uh
getting money from their parents yes and
I was like but we have the same income
so how how am I struggling and then I
was like oh other people have totally
different situations and was that the
first um step in kind of ex is that the
first step transparency is just but
that's so hard cuz no one talks about
money I grew up in a house where it was
like you you Nikki you don't tell your
friends how much your dad makes you're
not even if I wasn't allowed to know how
much money my dad made it wasn't like a
ton of money or it wasn't even or when
it wasn't a ton of money I wasn't
allowed to know either way why but in
the book I talk about I got such
Whiplash because my parents would go
through phases where they would have
some money and then they would nothing
too and so there would be days where
they'd be like oh yeah you could
definitely like go with your friends to
this like you know whatever you could
you could go to the dance with your
friends and get a new dress and then
like two days later they'd be like no
you can't I learned we destitute really
early on my dad would always say we're
destitute and I was like I don't know
what that and I had to like look it up
and I'm like oh no we're poor like I
felt the same back and forth of like do
we have all the money or none none of
the money and then I would get stressed
out like which is paraliz where I would
be like you know 12 and my parents would
spend money and I'd go should we be
doing this yes oh my God I remember the
day I I mean I remember the day I really
we were driving we were moving from
Cincinnati to St Louis I was six and I
remember being in the car and seeing the
St Louis Arch and just having a
realization I don't know what
conversation was happening between my
parents but I remember being like we're
poor like we're poor and I am the only
one that's going to make it so that my
sister doesn't spend my parents money so
I cuz they're not going to tell her so I
started like being like Lauren you can't
get I would like take her aside at
7eleven and be like you can only get one
candy Lauren EX I was protecting her
from my parents having to tell her and
just protecting my parents from not
being broke and fighting about it and
being scared like almost exactly the
same I have a little sister too yes and
she I interview her in the book and
she's like I had no concept I thought we
were fine I had no I I would if I she
was like if I asked Mom and Dad for
something and they said yes I would go
great we have the money so I started
being like telling her same I started
telling her you can't ask you have to
stop yes and then she got a lot of stuff
that I didn't get because I was like
well if she's in my mind because my
older brother also was like having
trouble finding a job at the time so
like they were helping him and so I
became like okay I should be successful
on my own because they're already
helping two of their kids so I need to
be the one that they don't help yes
which is so stressful to put on a
teenager yep I I took that I would
always be the one to take cuts and like
to to because I wanted I didn't want
them to know that I knew either like I
was trying to protect them from being
embarass F I don't need it exactly I
don't need it and then but I really
wanted it and I wanted all the things
that my friends were getting that and I
and you're right the transparency I
didn't understand like how does my
friend afford abian Fitch when her dad
has a similar job to my like I just
didn't understand it and I I still the
transparency thing is so huge in comedy
because I think that especially for
women we get paid less um than men a lot
of times and as comedians we're all so
private about what we're making and I'm
like no it shouldn't be private we
should all talk about it because we
should all be getting paid the same and
more and and I think that when you do
find out what someone makes you realize
oh I need to be asking for more I
deserve more um I had an interesting
experience where I was me and this girl
were both um speaking at a conference
and I she dm'd me to be like hey what
are they paying you and I was like oh
that's a great question so I told her
and she was like okay wow they're paying
me half of that so I said oh go to them
right now drop my name say Gabby told me
she's getting this and I want this yeah
and then they did they upped her fee
that's great and I was like for
absolutely for sure like everyone should
be doing that but people get so
uncomfortable when you know when they're
asked about how much money they make
both when they're not making enough and
when they're making too much when you're
making a lot of money I want to know
every scent that's why I always loved
being friends with Amy Schumer because I
realized because she was transparent
about it she wasn't bragging she was
just like can you believe the amount of
money I'm about to get for this thing
and she would tell me and so now I know
I have these like I know what I should
be making at different levels because I
saw her rise right where I kind of am
and so I know what to expect and I was
appreciative of her telling me that I
never took it as a brag even though some
people could have but I I felt like it
was it it let you your selfworth like it
let you know what you should ask for yes
it really did and um but I still
struggle even you know I'm at a point
now where I feel rich I feel like I
don't want for anything and I'm great
but there are days when I like if I
haven't I stress about money I I'll
still find ways to stress about money I
think it's something I go to much like
my weight or my hair or my skin where
you're just stressing about something
else and you need to find a place to put
it and so there there's a huge
difference between broke and poor and I
think I'm still pretty broke like I
think I have like problems with like
overspending or like you know I
immediately like my sister had a thing
where she was like I went to the dentist
and uh my tooth my her tooth fell out
and she's unemployed and so it was going
to cost her like $1,000 doar to get a
new tooth and I was like well you can't
be walking around without a tooth so I
was like all she was upset and I was
like I'll cover it yeah like just stuff
like that where I I still do it and I
have a friend who's an actress who was
like you got to stop that right now cuz
now PE now she knows that she can just
ask you for money but I'm not going to
let her walk around without a tooth like
I feel the same way I only want to make
more money because I want to pay for
people to get teeth that can't afford
teeth I mean I really do I hate the idea
of these expenses that come up in
people's lives like I've lent a last
year I got like uh my my money guy
called me and every year I dread the
call of like how what my spending was
the year because I don't look at my
budgeting I don't look at what I spend
on what and I kind of just know that he
sees it and is gonna judge me and he's
like you're not the the biggest things
you spend money on are lending people
giving away money yep and I and I'm glad
to I was glad to hear that because I've
never lent money and regret I I haven't
let money yet and regretted it I've
chosen good people to do it for but it
does feel like um it I I get I get
something more out of it sometimes than
I think the person does well what sucks
too is that there's so many medical
gofundmes and you just get them all the
time that's another thing gofundmes I
throw so much F of those I do too and
then um they're not they're considered
personal gifts they're not considered
donations so you can't write them off on
your taxes what really yes it's horrible
that's ridiculous yes so you can't write
them off on your there was an article I
just read that was like this girl got
some money for her cancer treatments and
then her taxes ended up being like
$119,000 on it oh my God right right so
she needs a Gund me for her tax for her
taxes I mean it's not set up our country
is not set up well I don't know if
anyone knows that but I
[Music]
it